<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Understanding the Bilingual Mind and Brain: Blog: Comments</title>
    <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</link>
    <description>Latest comments for Understanding the Bilingual Mind and Brain: Blog</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 16:54:56 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>http://www.movabletype.org/?v=4.38</generator>
    <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Hello Hong Kong!"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/06/hello-hong-kong.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Glad to hear you're getting settled in (I should have checked the blog sooner!).  The hills are really something and you'll get a workout.  &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- CAROL ANNE MILLER&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5295465@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 14:30:13 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "I spek gud Englis!"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/i-spek-gud-englis.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Exciting to hear that running participants is going well and the early results look good. It will be fun to see how things end up looking! Good luck&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- Alison Eisel Hendricks&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5293172@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 11:12:01 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Granada Update"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/granada-update.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hope you are feeling better now! The fair sounds like fun. Try to take pictures and post them! Enjoy the little break in participants before things get busy again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- Alison Eisel Hendricks&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5293171@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 11:08:09 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Language and Culture"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/language-and-culture-1.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What a great week! Nice to see the pictures too. I think one of the best parts of doing research on languages is that you also get to travel and enjoy the cultures! Great to hear that you are meeting people with similar research interests and getting to hear their experiences. Whenever you get to hear what not to do before you do it is helpful. Enjoy the rest of the trip!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- Alison Eisel Hendricks&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5293170@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 11:04:43 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Blog 2"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/blog-2.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You might consider looking into a mifi device to help you with the internet issue. Essentially, it's a mobile wifi hotspot that you can keep in your pocket, and in most countries, you can get one without a contract. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some mifi models are like USBs that you pop into your computer to use, but if you can find a standalone device, it would make it easy to use on the go with an iPod touch or a smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try stopping in a few cell phone shops around the city, and just ask if they carry them. If you do a bit of homework online first, it will probably also help you to figure out which stores might carry them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- COLLEEN PATRICIA BALUKAS&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5292533@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 14:16:23 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Confession: Public transportation scares me"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/confession-public-transportation-scares-me.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great story-telling! I completely understand the scariness of learning your way around a new bus system, especially in a new country. You never know what to expect! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strangely, I find the most chaotic bus systems are the most comfortable for me. Missed bus stops and non-functioning buttons? Totally irrelevant in a chaotic system, when a shout to the bus driver will stop the bus literally anywhere - even in the middle of a traffic jam, or two feet after the last person's invented stop. There's no way to go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you're getting the hang of everything now. I'm sure you'll get used to it all quickly!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- COLLEEN PATRICIA BALUKAS&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5292531@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 14:08:06 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Amsterdam: the City of Cheese"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/amsterdam-the-city-of-cheese.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wonderful pictures! It's great that you've already gotten into such a good work schedule, and that you still manage to find time to visit (and re-visit) different places around the country. And the appelflaps look divine.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- COLLEEN PATRICIA BALUKAS&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5292530@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 13:55:03 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Blog 2"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/blog-2.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel you on the Wifi situation. (I'm writing this right now while soaking in the internet at a cafe). I know there can be cultural differences in terms of how much internet people think is necessary for living (I think it's pretty high :) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good that the research has been going smoothly! It can be frustrating finding participants, but it sounds like things are picking up now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck running the participants!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- Alison Eisel Hendricks&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5292414@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 11:39:47 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Conquering the City and the Language"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/conquering-the-city-and-the-language.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great to hear your first week went well in Berlin! I'm also looking forward to seeing your pictures of Berlin and I hope you're getting to know your labmates and the city as well. Hope the next lab meeting goes as well as the first. Good Luck!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- Alison Eisel Hendricks&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5291973@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 13:52:34 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Conquering the City and the Language"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/conquering-the-city-and-the-language.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You've sold me! I wanna go to Berlin now, too! Also, I would NOT be able to understand anything from an ERP study presented in German, so I am impressed. I have a hard time following them in English ;) Keep up the good work - it sounds like you're doing great!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- AMELIA JANE DIETRICH&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5291967@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 12:36:25 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "My Attempt at Philosophical Thinking"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/my-attempt-at-philosophical-thinking.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben - Running on the streets, especially a la hora de tapas is probably also a give-away that you're not granadino! But that's ok. It's a very safe place. I walked the streets of Granada alone as a woman after dark and never had any issues/fears. And if you didn't explore those places on your runs, you might miss them completely! That would be a much bigger shame.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- AMELIA JANE DIETRICH&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5291966@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 12:30:32 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Week 1 - Getting acquainted"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/week-1---getting-acquainted-2.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;K2! How goes it? The trials of adjusting to a new lab are always frustrating. Have you had any more luck this week?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- AMELIA JANE DIETRICH&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5291965@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 12:24:09 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Week 1 - Introduction"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/week-1---introduction-1.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben - sounds like you're having a great experience. It's hard not to in Granada! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) You will FOREVER miss tapas once you leave Grana'...by the way, Granada is the only place they are always free and also fabulous. If you haven't hit up the tapas scene on Calle Elvira yet, you must! There's a bar run by Italians right inside la Puerta Elvira (near Caitlin's place) who always has good and different tapas (think: pasta? soup? fabulous!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Keep smiling through! It never hurts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and 3) Code-switching is not only a linguistic phenomenon, it is also a culturally constrained and community-based phenomenon. Our little bilingual community in Giuli's lab is a big fan of hablando whatever we want cuando sea but despite the presence of some highly proficient SLLs and a lot of foreign tourists, Granada is really a monolingual community. (Which is ok, because we often go there in search of monolinguals, right?)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- AMELIA JANE DIETRICH&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5291964@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 12:20:39 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Bicycles and stroopwafels"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/bicycles-and-stroopwafels.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good to know there's peanut butter in the Netherlands! My mom spent a fortune shipping it to me in Italy - a girl just can't live without that stuff! Also, that empty space where your peanut butter used to be in your suitcase can no be filled with cute European fashion. :) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- AMELIA JANE DIETRICH&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5291963@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 12:11:32 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Conquering the City and the Language"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/conquering-the-city-and-the-language.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Leah - I'm so pleased to hear that you made it to Berlin and are settling in! Congratulations on surviving that lab meeting in German (ERP studies in German could not have been an easy topic to understand!). It's also wonderful to hear that you've already tested 9 participants - way to go! As Dr. Dussias said above, I too look forward to seeing your pictures of the city! :)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- COURTNEY E J FOWLER&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5291943@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 09:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Confession: Public transportation scares me"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/confession-public-transportation-scares-me.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was very funny story. It sounds like a story I could have written but my ending would still be &quot;I still get lost and have no idea where I am or how to get home.&quot;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With your fantastic attitude, I have no doubt Nijmegen will be a wonderful experience for you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- PAOLA EULALIA DUSSIAS&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5291928@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 04:00:16 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "My Attempt at Philosophical Thinking"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/my-attempt-at-philosophical-thinking.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I knew exactly where you were! I get lost very easily in Granada, not because of the city layout, but because unlike you, I have no internal compass. Granada is a wonderful city to get lost in. No matter where you end up, you'll find a beautiful callejón. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thank you for sending me your first participant's data. I'll be looking at it this weekend. Can't wait to see what your first participant has done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abrazos!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- PAOLA EULALIA DUSSIAS&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5291927@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 03:43:56 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Conquering the City and the Language"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/conquering-the-city-and-the-language.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It sounds you've had a wonderful week and that you have may tools in your toolbox to get through challenging moments. I have never been to Berlin but have heard it is beautiful. Take lots of pictures! Looking forward to reading about your next adventure. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- PAOLA EULALIA DUSSIAS&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5291926@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 03:34:56 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "This is not Wales"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2013/05/this-is-not-wales.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Glad you're enjoying Wales and the unreal weather. Don't forget to post photos of the sheep! &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- COLLEEN PATRICIA BALUKAS&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment5270786@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 16:36:07 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Comment on "Watermelon in China"</title>
      <link>http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/2012/06/watermelon-in-china.html#comments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What a great entry to read first thing this morning! I love how you describe your walk to the university. I've never been to China, so I'm living through your descriptions and trying to imagine what it would be like! Good luck with your research!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;- COURTNEY E J FOWLER&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">comment3501902@http://cls.psu.edu/PIRE/blog/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 04:39:09 -0500</pubDate>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
